<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LatinR 2018</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://latinr.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://latinr.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Lunch places</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list of places near the Universidad de Palermo where you can go to lunch or have some coffee during the breaks. Note that we don’t have discount deals with them but we though it could be an useful list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can organise into groups in our Slack!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/La+Tolva/@-34.5976601,-58.4162985,19.42z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca880cde8405:0xa1c6e2f5c683d32b!8m2!3d-34.5978049!4d-58.4159569&quot;&gt;La Tolva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Cuyagua+Bar-Caf%C3%A9/@-34.5970784,-58.415678,20.42z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca87d8c630e1:0xa028239087960489!8m2!3d-34.597163!4d-58.4155042&quot;&gt;Cuyagua Bar Café&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Caf%C3%A9+Cort%C3%A1zar/@-34.596259,-58.4200987,18z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca7d11bfaf99:0xb9aabb9b59028870!8m2!3d-34.5964045!4d-58.41984&quot;&gt;Café Cortazar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Morillo/@-34.5975875,-58.4180104,19.42z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca880011cdaf:0xf5672f8a1a8a745b!8m2!3d-34.5976895!4d-58.4173583&quot;&gt;Morillo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Nazca,+Sabores+del+Per%C3%BA/@-34.5976601,-58.417004,19.42z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca8800d3ee09:0x4cd90d1ec89d2d73!8m2!3d-34.5977011!4d-58.4169392&quot;&gt;Nazca, Sabores del Perú&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Rinc%C3%B3n+Norte%C3%B1o/@-34.5970279,-58.4156166,19.18z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca87dba07cf9:0x7aa18730f5a558b6!8m2!3d-34.5967722!4d-58.4154526&quot;&gt;Rincón Norteño&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Bellagamba+Bodeg%C3%B3n/@-34.5967506,-58.4214943,20.01z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bcca7cf5428aaf:0xd66a446b75855bff!8m2!3d-34.5966242!4d-58.4214447&quot;&gt;Bellagamba Bodegón&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Le+Bl%C3%A9/@-34.5991268,-58.4183905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x95bccb72bb032a9d:0x207006fb017af38d!8m2!3d-34.5991312!4d-58.4161965&quot;&gt;Le Blé&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Bonafide/@-34.5959071,-58.4173874,17z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sbonafide!3m4!1s0x0:0xe93df5ff1d49318d!8m2!3d-34.5945272!4d-58.4140163&quot;&gt;Bonafide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/lunch-places</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/lunch-places</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Final preparations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;LatinR is just a few days from now and we are in the final preparations. We ask you, then, that you read carefully this information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;before-latinr&quot;&gt;Before LatinR&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We remind you that LatinR adheres to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://latin-r.com/coc/&quot;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We will use &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/latin-r/shared_invite/enQtNDA3MjM3MTQwOTM1LTRiZGM2Mjc0ZDU2YzE5OTBmYWRhNDRiYzMzY2M1MDk3MzNjOTUzZTdlZWMyZmJiZjYzMWE4Y2VkNTk0MWFmNDA&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; to keep in touch. If haven’t yet, we suggest you to join. It is a great space to resolve any issues about travel if you are coming to Buenos Aires. We will also be organising social activities there. To learn more about what Slack is and how it’s used we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/115004071768-What-is-Slack-&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During the conference we will be tweeting from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LatinR2018&quot;&gt;@LatinR2018&lt;/a&gt; with hashtag &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23latinr2018&quot;&gt;#LatinR2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Photos of the event will be published in different media and social networks. If you would prefer your pictures to not be published, please let us know &lt;strong&gt;before the event&lt;/strong&gt; so we can inform the photographers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On September 5th between 9 am and 1 pm there will be two simultaneous tracks, one for oral presentations and the other for a The Carpentries workshop. The latter will be in Spanish and has limited capacity and you can register &lt;a href=&quot;https://ti.to/carpentries/LatinR&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It is an excellent opportunity to get to know about this community, it’s instructors program and improve your teaching skills.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;during-latinr&quot;&gt;During LatinR&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Accreditation will start at 9 am on Monday September 3rd. Please &lt;strong&gt;take care of your credential&lt;/strong&gt; since it is the only way to access the activities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We recommend taking care of your personal belongings since we can’t be held responsible for loss, damaged or stolen property.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The organising team will have a pin with the LatinR logo so you can identify us easily.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for being part of this first version of LatinR!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/last-minute-preparations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/last-minute-preparations</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Financial aid to attend 47 JAIIO / LatinR2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sociedad Argentina de Informática (SADIO) is pleased to invite applications for financial aid scholarships for graduate students to attend the 47 JAIIO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To apply for this scholarship, each applicant must complete &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1EthSFVW02sZthNuq7-xeiLXteP48ok3qkWEycAljiM0/viewform?ts=5b54c7d5&amp;amp;edit_requested=true&quot;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish). The awarding of the scholarship does not exempt you from registering for the 47 JAIIOs. Instructions for registering for the 47 JAIIOs are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000/registration&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scholarships-details&quot;&gt;Scholarships details&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scholarships will provide financial aid to students in graduate programs in Computer Science/Information Technology/Systems Engineering/Computer Engineering or closely related fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be aimed at students who live more than 200 km from the city of Buenos Aires and who are interested in attending at least two days at 47 JAIIO. Selected applicants will receive financial aid of up to ARS 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recipients&quot;&gt;Recipients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scholarships will be mainly oriented to graduate students who are studying for a PhD outside the City of Buenos Aires. However, scholarships may also be awarded to Master’s degree students or advanced undergraduate students. Priority will be given to those who submit papers at 47 JAIIOs. The award of a scholarship does not exempt the recipient of the scholarship from its
registration at 47 JAIIO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;application-and-award-of-scholarships&quot;&gt;Application and award of scholarships&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants must complete the application by Auguts 6th 2018. The selected students will be informed on Auguts 16th 2018. In order to receive the stipend, which will take place at the JAIIO Offices, beneficiaries will be required to submit photocopies of their round-trip tickets, issued in their name, as well as a copy of the documentation to support the statements on their application form and sign proof of receipt of the scholarship award. Photocopies of tickets may NOT be replaced by other proofs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To apply for this scholarship, each applicant must fill out this form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sadio.org.ar/lists/lt.php?id=Y00KCAsGDgAOBUVVVldKB1MFUFc%3D&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary waves-effect waves-button waves-light waves-float&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Form&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/financial-aid</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/financial-aid</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LatinR Slack - Code of Conduct</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LatinR Slack is a virtual space dedicated to meet and share experiences with attendees, authors and organizers of LatinR before and during the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone in this workspace is required to agree with the following code of conduct. Organisers will enforce this code throughout the event and previous months. We expect cooperation from all participants to help ensure a safe environment for everybody. Please be welcoming, be kind and look out for each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want this to be a fun, friendly, and harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of gender, gender identity and expression, age, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, ethnicity, religion (or lack thereof), ideology or technology choices. We do not tolerate harassment of participants in any form. Discriminatory jokes and sexual language and imagery are not appropriate in any channel or direct messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants asked to stop any harassing behavior are expected to comply immediately. If a participant engages in harassing behavior, the conference organisers may take any action they deem appropriate, including warning the offender or expulsion from the workspace and/or the conference with no refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also we expect participants to follow these rules at conference and workshop venues and conference-related social events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;neep-help&quot;&gt;Neep help?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help about the use of Slack, please comment in the #dudas channel so everybody can help you. If you are being harassed, notice that someone else is being harassed, or have any other concerns, please contact the administrators immediately.  Conference staff will be happy to assist those experiencing harassment to feel safe for the duration of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://latin-r.com/coc/&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary waves-effect waves-button waves-light waves-float&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;47 JAIIO and LatinR Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://confcodeofconduct.com&quot;&gt;http://confcodeofconduct.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/coc-slack</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/coc-slack</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Talks contributed by our sponsors</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;productivity-in-r-with-rstudio&quot;&gt;Productivity in R with RStudio&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javier Luraschi, Software Engineer at RStudio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;: The creators of R provided a platform to process statistical computing freely and openly, which has enabled collaboration and extended its benefits worldwide; because it is better for everyone if the tools we use in scientific research are free and open. Making scientific software free has many benefits: it is reproducible, promotes greater sharing of knowledge and techniques, and removes cost barriers so that everyone can participate.
RStudio’s mission is to provide the best professional open source software with enterprise support for software applications and statistics using R. RStudio’s main product is an integrated development environment (IDE) that makes it easy for anyone to statistically analyze information with R. RStudio has also developed several packages for R, such as Shiny and R Markdown, which provide a platform for sharing interactive applications and reproducible reports. This session will introduce the tools and packages developed by RStudio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3d-printing-using-r&quot;&gt;3D printing using R&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucas Pogorelsky, Coordinator of the School of Data Science, Escuela Argentina de Nuevas Tecnologías (EANT)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: This talk aims to present how to use R to generate a representation of data in 3 dimensions and generate the necessary file for 3D printing and thus generate a “physical” graph. We will use data from the Buenos Aires subways from the Open Data Portal of the City of Buenos Aires and we will use the tidyverse libraries for structured data manipulation, sf for georeferencing data manipulation and r2stl for the generation of the stl file necessary for 3D printing. In the talk you will be able to see the map of the City of Buenos Aires with the number of passengers that get on each subway station printed in 3 dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 50 people to register for any aspect of LatinR2018 by July 9th, 2018 (tutorials and/or symposiums) will receive one month’s free access to the full content of the more than 100 courses on&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacamp.com/&quot;&gt;DataCamp.com&lt;/a&gt; (this subscription is equivalent to US$25).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/sponsor-talks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/sponsor-talks</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One month free subscription on DataCamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first works sent and accepted to LatinR will recieve, at the moment of registrarion, a free month subscription to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacamp.com/&quot;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt;, the leading platform for online learning for languages like R and Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most remarkable features of DataCamp is that, in addition to being able to complete isolated courses, it is possible to follow tracks with professional orientation (Data Scientist, Data Analyst, among others) or with skill orientation (for example, Data Visualization, Machine Learning , Time Series, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the fact that there are courses for both beginners and more advanced users, this benefit delivered by our sponsor will allow LatinR participants to continue developing their knowledge once the conference is over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/subscription-datacamp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/subscription-datacamp</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prices</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prices are in argentine pesos (ARS). The value in parenthesis corresonds to registrations after july 10th 2018. More information (in spanish) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://47jaiio.sadio.org.ar/index.php?q=como_inscribirse&quot;&gt;JAIIO’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table-price&quot;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tableizer-firstrow&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;1st article / &lt;br /&gt; Attendance&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt; Additional article&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;General&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$2.000 ($2600)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$1.000 ($1.300)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;JAIIO member (2)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$1.000 ($1.300)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$500 ($600)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Teacher (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$1.200 ($1560)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$600 ($780)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Doctoral Student (3)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$1.200 ($1560)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$600 ($780)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Graduate student (author JAIIO symposium)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$1.200 ($1560)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$600 ($780)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Graduate student (author EST Contest) (4) (5)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$600 ($780)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$300 ($390)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Graduate student (attendance) (4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$600 ($780)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;- &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Graduate student JAIIO member (attendance) (4)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$300 ($390)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;- &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every article presented in JAIIO must have an associated author inscription. Payment for additional articles will be applied only to the 2nd and 3rd articles to be registered by the same author. Registration must be paid before July 9, 2018 for the work to be published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Members of SADIO, IEEE, AADECA or EPIO. You must attach proof that you prove your affiliation to that institution and have your payments up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) Teachers and graduate students must prove this condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) Students must show regular student documents at the time of registration. The benefit is for first carreer students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(4) Students authors of the EST Contest may only present their work in said contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consult for student packages and for registration of groups of 10 or more participants at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:información@sadio.org.ar&quot;&gt;información@sadio.org.ar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prices-for-tutorials&quot;&gt;Prices for tutorials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tutorials prior to the confference have an aditional cost. The value in parenthesis is for prople not registered at JAIIO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table-price&quot;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tableizer-firstrow&quot;&gt;&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;padding:0 15px 0 15px;&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Day and time&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Price in ARS&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Visualización estática e interactiva de datos usando ggplot2 y plotly by Natalia da Silva&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Monday Sep 3rd&lt;br /&gt; 10 to 13hs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$400 ($1000)&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Inteligencia artificial con R: Introducción al &quot;Deep Learning&quot; by Andrés Farrall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Monday Sep 3rd &lt;br /&gt; 10 to 13hs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$400 ($1000)&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;T3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;purrr: Functional Programming Mindset by Jennifer Bryan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Monday Sep 3rd&lt;br /&gt; 14 to 18hs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$400 ($1000)&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;T4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Aspectos de seguridad en el desarrollo de aplicaciones Cloud by Pablo Frías and Eduardo Sánchez&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Tuesday Sep 4th &lt;br /&gt; 9 to 13hs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$400 ($1000)&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/prices</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/prices</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for Papers</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;latinr---latin-american-conference-about-the-use-of-r-in-research--development&quot;&gt;LatinR &amp;lt;- Latin American Conference about the Use of R in Research + Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The Argentinian Informatics Society (Sociedad Argentina de Informática, 
SADIO) is organizing the inaugural LatinR symposium within the 47th Argentinian Meeting of Informatics and Operational Research (Jornadas Argentinas de Informática e Investigación Operativa, JAIIO) that will take place between September 4 and 5, 2018 in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JAIIO proposes an interdisciplinary approach to socio-technical problems and practices that emerge from the rapid advance of information and communication technologies in society. We invite researchers, technologists, developers, educators, and companies to submit abstracts related to the use of the R programming environment, ranging from research and experimental instances to
applications, demonstrations of applications, and commercial use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;topics-of-interest&quot;&gt;Topics of interest&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications of R in academic and industrial disciplines. We would like to cover all fields of knowledge in an interdisciplinary way (e.g., Data Science, Statistics, Informatics, Biological and Health Sciences, Bioinformatics, Geology, Atmospheric Sciences, Social Sciences, Humanities,
Economy, Finance, Business, Journalism, …)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications of R together with other programming languages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovative uses of existing R packages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New R packages
R packages development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovative uses of R in education&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reproducible data analysis using R&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big data and R&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine learning and R&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R visualization tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open data analysis with R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;important-dates&quot;&gt;Important dates&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract submission deadline: &lt;del&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 13, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;April 30, 2018&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Abstract acceptance notification: &lt;strong&gt;June 22, 2018&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Abstract final version submission and author registration deadlines: &lt;strong&gt;July 9, 2018&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
LatinR: &lt;strong&gt;September 4-5, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;abstract-submissions&quot;&gt;Abstract submissions&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All abstracts submitted must be related to LatinR’s topics of interest. We will accept oral communications and posters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;oral-communications&quot;&gt;Oral communications&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three formats for oral communications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communications about research results, progress reports, or specific developments of interest to the regional community of R users. These oral communications are for work not previously published or presented in any other event. The submission must include an extended abstract, with a maximum length of 2 pages, including keywords, texts, and figures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communications about works previously presented in an international event outside of Latin America or published in an international non-Latin American journal during the years 2016 to 2018. The goal of these communications is that active researchers disseminate work of wide international interest within Latin America. These oral communications will require submitting a one-page abstract including the abstract of the original publication together with the event/journal, date, URL Access, or DOI where it was previously published.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demonstration of an application (demo) where authors can present results of projects developed using R (e.g., Shiny applications or other platforms that include the use of R). This type of oral communications will have the possibility of obtaining feedback from potential users, as well as, the development of particularly innovative applications or processes in private
companies or by independent professionals. The aim of demos is to exchange experiences acquired in practice. Success cases are as welcome as cases of problems encountered with the application of a specific methodology or technology. The submission of oral communications of a demo should include: (i) a one-page abstract describing the application or process, its objectives, problems it solves, audience of users for whom it is intended, and technology used and (ii) a URL of a version of the demo if applicable (in cases it can be executed online) or, alternatively, a URL with a short (5 minutes maximum) video showing demo’s main features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All oral communications accepted will be orally presented during LatinR. The abstracts of the oral communications will be included in LatinR Annals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;posters&quot;&gt;Posters&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posters allow researchers and professionals to present and discuss their latest advances, ideas, ongoing research, and experiences or challenges related to the topics of interest of LatinR. Posters submissions must include a one-page abstract, including all text, tables and figures. Accepted abstracts will be included in the LatinR Annals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;common-format-for-all-abstracts&quot;&gt;Common format for all abstracts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstracts must be written in Spanish, Portuguese, or English and must comply with the LNCS (Lecture Notes in Computer Science) format, with A4 sheet size and 10 point typography. The following templates provided by Springer should be used (also downloadable from &lt;a href=&quot;http://47jaiio.sadio.org.ar/formatos&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/Ejemplo_Word_Demostracion_LatinR.doc&quot;&gt;Abstracts for Demos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/Ejemplo_Word_Poster_LatinR.doc&quot;&gt;Abstract for Posters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/Ejemplo_Word_ExtendedAbstract_LatinR.doc&quot;&gt;Extended abstract for unpublished oral communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/Ejemplo_Word_ComunicacionOral_LatinR_2018.doc&quot;&gt;Short abstract for previously published oral communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All abstracts must be submitted in PDF format, without authors or affiliation until the review process is completed. Abstracts must have enough space to include, in its final version, all authors and affiliations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract submissions to any of the 47 JAIIO Symposia will proceed through 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sgc.sadio.org.ar/sgc/index.php&quot;&gt;SADIO’s conference management system&lt;/a&gt;. To submit your work you need to be registered (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://sgc.sadio.org.ar/sgc/index.php/index/index/user/account&quot;&gt;register&lt;/a&gt;) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://sgc.sadio.org.ar/sgc/index.php/index/index/login&quot;&gt;access the system&lt;/a&gt;. For further information and frequently asked questions, please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://47jaiio.sadio.org.ar/index.php?q=envio-trabajos&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All abstracts will be reviewed by the members of the Scientific Committee, taking into account their originality, contribution, technical quality, and clarity. At least one of the authors of accepted abstracts must be registered for JAIIO before July 9, 2018 to be included LatinR Annals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least one author of accepted abstracts is required to attend LatinR on the date and time indicated in the program. Be aware that works whose authors do not attend to the presentation will be removed from LatinR Annals. In case of a major emergency, authors may send a duly authorized representative to present work on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/call-for-papers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/call-for-papers</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to become a sponsor of 47 JAIIO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;47 JAIIO, 47th Jornadas Argentinas de Informática, will take place at Palermo
University, in Buenos Aires, Argentina, from September 3rd to September 7th, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are the sponsorship levels available to support the 47th JAIIO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;1-principal-sponsor-for-the-47th-jaiio&quot;&gt;1° Principal Sponsor for the 47th JAIIO&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization has three (3) hours available for presentations, receives fifty (50) registrations to all JAIIO events, can exhibit its banners in the 47 JAIIO rooms during the five conference days, and may install a commercial stand.   &lt;br /&gt;
The organization’s logo will be printed in the front banner and in the main room banner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;2-event-sponsor&quot;&gt;2° Event Sponsor:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(for 1 (one) JAIIO Symposium or specific event)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization has two (2) hours available for presentations, receives forty (40) registrations to all JAIIO events, can exhibit its banners in the 47 JAIIO rooms during the days of the Symposium and may install a commercial stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;3-regular-sponsor&quot;&gt;3° Regular Sponsor&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization has one (1) hour available for presentations, receives thirty (30) registrations to all JAIIO events and may install a commercial stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;4-main-advertiser&quot;&gt;4° Main Advertiser&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization has thirty minutes (30 minutes) available for presentations and receives fifteen (15) registrations to all JAIIO events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;5-regular-advertiser&quot;&gt;5° Regular Advertiser&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization receives ten (10) registrations to all JAIIO events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;additionals&quot;&gt;Additionals&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30-minutes presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commercial stand installation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In case you are interested in other promotional activities, let us know and we will provide you with additional information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT: In all cases, logos will be included in JAIIO deliverables and in the web site, according to the position acquired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information visit &lt;a href=&quot;www.47jaiio.sadio.org.ar&quot;&gt;www.47jaiio.sadio.org.ar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in sponsoring 47 JAIIO, please write us at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;mailto:latinr@47jaiio.sadio.org.ar?subject=Patrocinar LarinR&quot;&gt;latinr@47jaiio.sadio.org.ar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//blog/sponsor-latinr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//blog/sponsor-latinr</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>JAIIO Code of Conduct</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone at our conference are required to agree with the following code of conduct. Organisers will enforce this code throughout the event. We expect cooperation from all participants to help ensure a safe environment for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;need-help&quot;&gt;Need Help?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have our contact details at the bottom of each Simposium’s webpage at &lt;a href=&quot;http://47jaiio.sadio.org.ar/simposios&quot;&gt;http://47jaiio.sadio.org.ar/simposios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-quick-version&quot;&gt;The Quick Version&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JAIIO is dedicated to providing a harassment-free conference experience for everyone, regardless of gender, gender identity and expression, age, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, ethnicity, religion (or lack thereof), ideology or technology choices. We do not tolerate harassment of conference participants in any form. Sexual language and imagery is not appropriate for any conference venue, including talks, workshops, parties, Twitter, and other online media. Conference participants violating these rules may be sanctioned or expelled from the conference without a refund at the discretion of the conference organisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-less-quick-version&quot;&gt;The Less Quick Version&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harassment includes offensive verbal comments related to gender, gender identity and expression, age, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, ethnicity, religion, ideology, technology choices, sexual images in public spaces, deliberate intimidation, stalking, following, harassing photography or recording, sustained disruption of talks or other events, inappropriate physical contact, and unwelcome sexual attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants asked to stop any harassing behavior are expected to comply immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a participant engages in harassing behavior, the conference organisers may take any action they deem appropriate, including warning the offender or expulsion from the conference with no refund.
If you are being harassed, notice that someone else is being harassed, or have any other concerns, please contact a member of conference staff immediately. Conference staff can be identified as they’ll be wearing branded badges.
Conference staff will be happy to help participants contact venue security, provide escorts, or otherwise assist those experiencing harassment to feel safe for the duration of the conference. We value your attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect participants to follow these rules at conference and workshop venues and conference-related social events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://confcodeofconduct.com&quot;&gt;http://confcodeofconduct.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://latinr.github.io//coc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://latinr.github.io//coc/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
